Transparent icon support added! All the bitmap files were converted to icon files and the code was updated to support that. Turns out this is a whole thing in Win32 land! Anyway now things look much better! Almost there!
App icon updated. It now has a good looking high quality .ico file with multiple sizes and bit depths!
Created a first draft for the About dialog box image.
Fixed About Box Crashes! Took out some malloc code that wasn't needed and took out some pointer stuff that wasn't right for 64-bit systems even though this is a Win32 application. Also put everything in place for the new About dialog box. Just need to update the graphic! Also added a button for a credits file and a menu item for a readme file.
Created new and updated all of the buttons and icons! The only remaining items for the GUI refresh are a new ADF Opus 2025 application .ico icon file with multiple sizes and a new Above dialog box redesign and image. I'm taking inspiration from the About dialog box design from the 25.2.5.2 (X86_64) of Libre Office. Almost there on a whole upgraded look and feel!
Update one last icon for now and added the Invert Selection to the right click menu.
Many bmp files used for icons were updated! Will do another release once all the icons have been refreshed for a more polished and modern look!
Update labels working! Now you can relabel a disk image's disk name! Just open the Disk Information dialog box and pick the Volume tab. Then edit the text area with the disk label and hit the Update Label button. You're disk is now relabeled! This includes some small fixes that eliminated warnings.
Update labels working! Now you can relabel a disk image's disk name! Just open the Disk Information dialog box and pick the Volume tab. Then edit the text area with the disk label and hit the Update Label button. You're disk is now relabeled!
Adding an Update Label button. Next step: make it go!
Write and Save boot blocks too and from disk images! Either install them so they boot properly or raw write them if you'd like. You can view boot blocks in hex, copy them to the clipboard, or save them as text files or in binary .bbk format!
Greaseweazle autowrites DD or HD! It looks at the type of disk image the adf is and sets double-density or high-density automatically. So when you go to write a disk you don't have to set anything - it gets detected and automatically passed to Greaseweazle! Just make sure you have a floppy disk drive that supports high-density disks and an Amiga that also has a high-density disk drive!
HEX Viewer Added! Now you can either quickly view a file in hexidecimal. I used the name "HEX Viewer" simply because "Text" and "Hex" looked to similar and it was easy to pick the wrong one. Also I made non-editable fields look that way instead of being editable but not actually doing anything.
Hex Bootblock: Updated the boot block viewer to show a hex view instead of text as most of time all you'd see is "DOS" at the top and that's it. This is a proper hex view which is way more useful. Might even find some virus boot blocks in your disk images! Haha!
Greaseweazle supported! You can read and write disks from within ADF Opus 2025! The write dialog box now shows you the density for the selected disk image as either Double Denisty or High Density.
Greaseweazle support added! Can read and write floppy disks without having to leave the app! Just need to finish up a few details to get writing to HD disk supported properly and automatically...
Made the Greaseweazle dialog box a bit better in layout.
Very basic Greaseweazle disk image reading now working!
Added: Auto Path on ADF Open - When you're in Window Explorer and you double-click an ADF file the program extracts the proper path and filename and opens the ADF file. At this time we take the path from the filename of the ADF we've opened and use that as the default folder to open on the local file system window instead of the current default which is the user's home folder.
Fixed the Text Viewer issue where the last line of text isn't showing. This reads it all in one go and converts the line endings!
Disabled DISK2FDI and converted the dialogs to the up and coming Greaseweazle feature. Note: This doesn't implement it yet!
Updated the readme for the GitHub page.
Logo updated for a tighter crop on the ADF Opus 2025 GitHub readme page.
Quick update to crop the GitHub page logo for ADF Opus.
Reworked the way icons are handled so it's easier to manage and update icons. Also added some quick icons where there were none. This is setting the stage for a future overhaul of all the icons. A few other fixes as well!
Update README.md
Update README.md
Added screenshot.
Merge branch 'main' of https://github.com/chironb/ADFOpus2025
Fix: About: Stops crashes sometimes when you click any of the buttons that open a web page. Also fixed the .rc issues so now you can use the resource editing features inside VS.
Update README.md
Updated the GitHub link button in About.
Add project files.
